<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<post>
  <author>tracker1</author>
  <title>JavaScript Books That Should Be Required Reading</title>
  <description>These are some of my recommended books for reading and getting a better grasp on JavaScript.</description>
  <content>&lt;div&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		I often get asked what books I recommend for developers looking to get 
		more into JavaScript.  Often they're looking for something specific to a 
		given framework, most often jQuery.  Although there are some great jQuery 
		and a couple of jQueryUI books as well, I'd recommend the following books 
		first and formost for those with some knowledge of JavaScript, but wanting
		to get a better grasp.
	&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		The first half of this year I read through eight recently published 
		books centered around JavaScript and these are the one's I would 
		recommend.  
	&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		&lt;div style="float:left;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0596517742?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=frugcode-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0596517742"&gt;&lt;img src="/image.axd?picture=2010%2f9%2fjavascript-the-good-parts.jpg" alt="Book Cover--JavaScript: The Good Parts" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0596517742?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=frugcode-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0596517742"&gt;JavaScript: The Good Parts&lt;/a&gt; 
		is one of two JavaScript books that I feel should be required reading for all 
		web developers.  Even if you've jumped into JS and don't care to start 
		with entry level re-hashes, this is a great read.  I don't agree 100% 
		with &lt;a href="http://javascript.crockford.com/"&gt;Douglas Crockford&lt;/a&gt;'s 
		views.  However, this is a great read that will give some insightful 
		concepts and ideas.  Also worth looking at is 
		&lt;a href="http://www.yuiblog.com/crockford/"&gt;Crockford's video series on YUI Blog&lt;/a&gt;.
		&lt;br style="clear:left;"/&gt;
	&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p style="clear:left;margin-top:1em;"&gt;
		&lt;div style="float:left;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0596522304?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=frugcode-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0596522304"&gt;&lt;img src="/image.axd?picture=2010%2f9%2feven-faster-web-sites.jpg" alt="Book Cover--Even Faster Web Sites" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0596522304?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=frugcode-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0596522304"&gt;Even Faster Web Sites: Performance Best Practices for Web Developers&lt;/a&gt; 
		is the other book I feel should be required reading for all web developers, 
		and even designers.  It covers a lot of great examples of how JavaScript 
		and other elemental decisions in the design and markup of a site impact 
		performance.  There isn't as much specific to JS as 
		&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/059680279X?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=frugcode-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=059680279X"&gt;High Performance JavaScript (Build Faster Web Application Interfaces)&lt;/a&gt;, 
		which is another good read. There's about a 50% overlap between the two 
		books, and I feel that the former is a much more important read and 
		reading both will get very redundant, very quickly. [more]
	&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		&lt;br /&gt;Along with the books above, I would also suggest taking a look at the following books as well...
&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		&lt;div style="float:left;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0596101996?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=frugcode-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0596101996"&gt;&lt;img src="/image.axd?picture=2010%2f9%2fjavascript-the-definitive-guide.jpg" alt="Book Cover--JavaScript: The Definitive Guide" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0596101996?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=frugcode-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0596101996"&gt;JavaScript: The Definitive Guide&lt;/a&gt; 
		is a book that every beginning web developer should have on their bookshelf.  If you 
		want a more novice friendly text, I would suggest the 
		&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0470526912?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=frugcode-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0470526912"&gt;JavaScript Bible&lt;/a&gt;
		(&lt;em&gt;I'm linking to the 2010 version, which should be out in October.&lt;/em&gt;).  
		The definitive guide is a bit better as a reference text, the bible is 
		better as a learning text.
		&lt;br style="clear:left;"/&gt;
	&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p style="clear:left;margin-top:1em;"&gt;
		&lt;div style="float:left;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/159059908X?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=frugcode-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=159059908X"&gt;&lt;img src="/image.axd?picture=2010%2f9%2fpro-javascript-design-patterns.jpg" alt="Book Cover--Pro JavaScript Design Patterns" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/159059908X?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=frugcode-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=159059908X"&gt;Pro JavaScript Design Patterns&lt;/a&gt; is another book worth looking at.
		Though I honestly feel that there will usually be simpler solutions to 
		most given problems, reading this book provides a gateway to several good 
		thought experiments and can provide some insightful ideas on how to 
		resolve some common issues with design patterns.
		&lt;br style="clear:left;"/&gt;
	&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		If you're first starting out, I would go through The 
		Definitive Guide, before looking into The Good Parts, or Even Faster 
		Web Sites.  Beyond this, there are a lot of blogs out there covering 
		JavaScript from many different vantage points, and lots of frameworks 
		and tools out there.  I feel that these books are a great starting 
		point to understanding JavaScript better and a greater understanding of 
		how JavaScript works, instead of blindly cutting and pasting framework 
		examples.
	&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>True</ispublished>
  <iscommentsenabled>True</iscommentsenabled>
  <pubDate>2010-09-15 10:38:00</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2010-10-29 14:13:56</lastModified>
  <raters>0</raters>
  <rating>0</rating>
  <slug>javascript-books-2010</slug>
  <tags>
    <tag>javascript</tag>
    <tag>books</tag>
  </tags>
  <comments />
  <categories>
    <category>e8ec79a6-7f5d-46e5-b7d5-0a35e8e08c95</category>
    <category>ae364b53-e11b-4d02-9d51-b2accb9a63e9</category>
  </categories>
  <notifications />
</post>